Hello.
So here we will be talking about the introduction to contactless cards.
So contactless smart card is a smart card that uses inductive coupling to communicate with its reader.
Inductive coupling in fact, is the technology behind NFC, near-field communication, and short range
RFID for for radio frequency identification in the 1350 six megahertz radio band.
So high frequency radio band proximity contactless smart cards are defined by the ISO 14,443 set of
international standards.
The ISO 14,443 is divided into four layers.
The upper layers, which is ISO 14,443 four, specifies the contactless transport protocol, sometimes
referred to as T equal CL, CL for contactless.
The application layer that comes on top of the contactless protocol is supposed to be the very same
ISO 7008 16 dash four that comes on top of the T equals zero or t equal one.
Transport protocols.
As you can see here, I put some example of the contactless technology like car keys, passports, bags,
identification or bags, tags, transport, uh, cars, transportation or like medicine tax.
So a lot of contactless cards on the market today are not smart cards, but wired logic memories with
an RF interface.
So the marketing gives them different names like RFID labels, NFC tags, contactless tickets, but
they are all based on the same physical principle inductive coupling at 1350 six megahertz.
Please remember always that here when we talk about the contactless communication, we are in the range
of the 1350 six megahertz.
This is the frequency that characterizes that characterize this technology and are all compliant with
either ISO 14,143 standard for proximity cards, or ISO 15 15,693 standard for vicinity cards.
So here we will be talking about the coupling device or coupler, or let's say the reader.
Now that we know that a smart card is basically a secure microcontroller communicating with the external
world through a serial line, we must find a better name than reader for the device that ensures the
connectivity and gives access to the smart card instructions.
Even if the term smart card reader has been popularized by the Pcsc and Ccid specifications, it does
not reflect the technical reality, because a card's instruction set opens lots more features than just
reading some data.
Reading a smart card makes not more sense than reading a remote web server or reading an SQL database.
You do not read a raw memory.
In fact, your application sends some commands to get authenticated since other commands to explore
a file system sends commands also to insert or update or delete the data.
Or read it, of course, but not only.
Therefore, the device in which the smart card is inserted plays the role of a pass through gateway
between a software running in the host computer or host terminal, and the software running inside the
card's microcontroller.
This pass through gateway translates commands coming from the host application through either USB,
serial Ethernet, or any other computer interconnection technology into electronic signals that are
compliant with the asynchronous half duplex.
Serial T equals zero or T equal one transport protocol, but this gateway does not add any processing
logic.
Its position is to couple the smart card with the computer.
As a consequence, the standard name as defined by the ISO 7816 is coupling device CD or simply a coupler.
Contactless coupler are in turn named Proximity Coupling Device or PCD by the ISO 14,443 or vicinity
coupling device vxd by the ISO 15,693.
So we were talking about the PCD.
Now we will be talking about the Picc components.
As you can see here in this picture, the card and the reader unit communicates with each other through
125kHz radio frequency fields.
So 30 56MHz for the contactless smart card cards by a process called resonant energy transfer.
Passive cards have three components which are sealed inside the plastic.
Inside the plastic, we have an antenna consisting of a coil of of wire, a capacitor and integrated
circuit.
So as I said, the the course is is composed by three components, as you can see here in the picture.
So as I said it contains an antenna consisted of a coil of wire, a capacitor and integrated circuit
which contains the user's ID number in specific formats and no other data.
The reader has its own antenna, which continuously transmits a short range radio frequency field.
When the card is placed within range of the reader, the antenna coil and capacitor, which form a tuned
circuit absorb and store energy from the field, resonating at the frequency emitted by the reader.
This energy is rectified to direct current, which powers the integrated circuit.
The chip sends its ID number or other data to the antenna coil, which transmits it by radio frequency
signals back to the reader unit.
The reader checks whether the ID number from the card is correct, and then performs whatever function
it has been programmed to do for that ID number.
All the energy to power the card comes from the reader unit, so passive cards must be close to a reader
to transmit their data.
So the first part here we will be talking on how the card is fabricated.
So the exchange of information between the contactless card and the associated reader is completely
accomplished by remote electromagnetic coupling between an antenna lodged in the contactless card and
the second antenna located in the reader for developing, storing and processing the information.
The card is equipped with a contactless chip or electronic module which is connected to the antenna.
The antenna and the chip or contactless module are typically located on a dielectric.
Dielectric support made of plastic material can be PVC, polyester, polycarbonate, etc. the antenna
here is obtained by chemical, copper or aluminium etching on the support or winding or winding of conductive
metal wire, such as a copper.
The card is often monoblock.
The antenna support is inserted between two layers of plastic materials PVC, Pet, PC, etc., forming
the upper and lower card bodies and then heat bonded by hot lamination under pressure.
The contactless chip or module is connected to the antenna by an electrically conductive glue or equivalent,
which enables the ohmic contact to be established.
So here we are in the summary.
So as I said before, a pick is a contactless card that uses inductive coupling to communicate with
the reader.
All picks are based on the same physical principle inductive coupling at 1350 six megahertz.
The card and the reader unit communicate with each other through 125kHz radio frequency field by a process
called resonant energy transfer.
And finally, the exchange of information between the contactless card and the associated reader is
accomplished by remote electromagnetic coupling between an antenna loaded in the contactless card and
the second antenna located in the reader.